Vipin Gopinath

UI/Backend Developer

Address 8-35/5, Plot No 42

New Hemanagar, Hyderabad-39,India

Phone +91 8977357398

Email vipin.vipin.q498@gmail.com

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/vipin-gopinath7/

https://github.com/viping7

https://www.facebook.com/vipin.gopinath.92

https://viping7.github.io/portfolio/

Skills

Front-end Development

HTML/CSS/SCSS

★★★☆ Expert

Javascript/ Jquery

★★☆☆ Intermediate

Angular Js / Angular

★★★☆ Expert

React / React-Redux

★ ★ ☆ ☆ Intermediate

Back-end Development

Node Js / Express Js

★★★☆ Expert

Loopback / Sails.js

★★☆☆ Intermediate

PHP

★☆☆☆ Beginner

Database

MySQL

★★☆☆ Intermediate

MongoDB

★★☆☆ Intermediate

About Me

I am 24 year old UI/Backend Engineer from kerala, currently living in Hyderabad, India. I have a passion for creating beautiful, intuitive, and highly crafted solutions combining a considered approach with emerging technologies. I like going through new stuffs which includes tech and tv series during my freetime.

Work Experience

Monocept

Senior Software Engineer, March 2018 - Present

Responsible for making microservices and monolithic applications using node.js frameworks like loopbackjs, sailsJs and templating engines like Ejs.

Works also include converting awesome designs into efficient and high performing web applications with easily managable code and effortless integration using technologies like Angular JS, Angular, React, jQuery, HTML 5, SASS and build tools like gulp.

F1 Studioz

UI Engineer, July 2016 - Feb 2018

Responsible for converting awesome designs into efficient and high performing web applications with easily managable code and effortless integration.

Works include client side development of rich javascript applications by leveraging power of technologies like Angular JS, Angular, React, jQuery, HTML 5, SASS and build tools like gulp.

Worked closely with designers and backend developers to deliver pixel perfect and efficient web apps and sites.

Projects

Barclays's Origami - Goal Planner

Technologies Used - Angular Js, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Jquery.

Role - Developer

Barclay's Origami project is to create a life's goal planner for customer which helps in knowing how much money needs to be saved to achieve a particular goal.

Data and flow persistency to create a detailed savings reports

Spotcap

Technologies Used - HTML , CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Node.js , Sails.js, Ejs Role - Full Stack Developer

A Webapp that allows companies to apply for credilines and get approved if the criteria is met.

Includes multiple microservices from document recognition engine to translation services and a back end sytem to verify user identity and approve creditline

Max Life Insurance - CSG

Technologies Used - , Nodejs , Loopback

Role - Api Developer

A hybrid app for agents to keep track of prospect leads and existing leads. Also provides way to generate a customized plan for the lead based on few criterias.

Education

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering (2012-2016)

Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University I St. Mary's College of Engg. and Tech

10th and 10+2 (2010-2012)

Kendriya Vidyalaya Ottapalam, Kerala